<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Solar System</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="nav_header_title">Android Studio</string>
    <string name="nav_header_subtitle">android.studio@android.com</string>
    <string name="nav_header_desc">Navigation header</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>

    <string name="menu_home">Home</string>
    <string name="menu_gallery">Gallery</string>
    <string name="menu_slideshow">Slideshow</string>

    <string name="nav_planets"><b>Planets</b></string>
    <string name="nav_other"><b>Other</b></string>

    <string name="home_second">Home Second</string>

    <string-array name="text_sizes">
        <item>Small Text Size</item>
        <item>Normal Text Size</item>
        <item>Large Text Size</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="solar_system_info">Our planetary system is located in an outer spiral arm of
        the Milky Way galaxy.\n
        \nOur solar system consists of our star, the Sun, and everything bound to it by gravity —
        the planets Mercury, Venus, Earth, Mars, Jupiter, Saturn, Uranus and Neptune,
        dwarf planets such as Pluto, dozens of moons and millions of asteroids, comets and
        meteoroids. Beyond our own solar system, we have discovered thousands of planetary systems
        orbiting other stars in the Milky Way.\n
        \n<b>What We Know So Far:</b>
        \n<b>Age:</b> 4.6 Billion Years
        \n<b>Number of Planets:</b> 8
        \n<b>Number of Dwarf Planets:</b> 5
        \n<b>Number of Moons:</b> 200+
        \n<b>Number of Comets:</b> 3,633
        \n<b>Number of Asteroids:</b> 958,263
        \n<b>Diameter:</b> 18.75 trillion kilometers
    </string>

    <string name="potential_for_life"><b>Potential for Life</b>
        \nOur solar system is the only place we know of that harbors life, but the farther we explore
        the more we find potential for life in other places. Both Jupiter’s moon Europa and Saturn’s
        moon Enceladus have global saltwater oceans under thick, icy shells.
    </string>

    <string name="mercury_info">Mercury is the closest planet to the sun. As such, it circles the
        sun faster than all the other planets, which is why Romans named it after their
        swift-footed messenger god.\n
        \nAccording to NASA, the atmosphere of Mercury is a surface-bound exosphere,
        essentially a vacuum. It contains 42 percent oxygen, 29 percent sodium, 22 percent hydrogen,
        6 percent helium, 0.5 percent potassium, with possible trace amounts of argon, carbon dioxide,
        water, nitrogen, xenon, krypton and neon.\n
        \n<b>Did You Know?</b>
        \nBecause of Mercury\'s elliptical—egg-shaped—orbit and sluggish rotation, the morning Sun
        appears to rise briefly, set and rise again from some parts of the planets surface.
        The same thing happens in reverse at sunset.
    </string>
    <string name="mercury_facts"><b>Average distance from Sun:</b> 57.9 million km
        \n<b>Size (radius):</b> 2,439.7 km
        \n<b>Size (Compared to Earth):</b>  0.38 time the size of Earth
        \n<b>Mass:</b> 3.285 × 10^23 kg (0.055 M⊕)
        \n<b>Length of Day:</b> 58d 15h 30m
        \n<b>Length of Year:</b> 88 days
        \n<b>Planet Type:</b> Terrestrial
        \n<b>Number of Moons:</b> None
        \n<b>Surface Temperature:</b> Day: 430 Celsius, Night: -180 Celsius
    </string>

    <string name="venus_info">Although it is the second planet from the sun, Venus is the hottest
        planet in the solar system. The reason Venus is hotter than even Mercury is not because of
        its position in the solar system but because of its thick, dense cloud layer.\n
        \nRoughly two-thirds of the Venusian surface is covered by flat, smooth plains that are
        marred by thousands of volcanoes, some of which are still active today, ranging from about
        0.5 to 150 miles (0.8 to 240 kilometers) wide, with lava flows carving long, winding canals
        that are up to more than 3,000 miles (5,000 km) in length — longer than on any other planet.\n
        \n<b>Did You Know?</b>
        \nThe Soviet Union’s Venera 13 survived the intense heat and crushing pressure of Venus’
        surface for more than two hours. Engineers from several nations are currently studying
        methods to extend the life of robotic spacecraft in the extreme environment.
    </string>
    <string name="venus_facts"><b>Average distance from Sun:</b> 108 million km
        \n<b>Size (radius):</b> 6,051.8 km
        \n<b>Size (Compared to Earth):</b>  0.9499 time the size of Earth
        \n<b>Mass:</b> 4.867 × 10^24 kg (0.815 M⊕)
        \n<b>Length of Day:</b> 116d 18h 0m
        \n<b>Length of Year:</b> 225 days
        \n<b>Planet Type:</b> Terrestrial
        \n<b>Number of Moons:</b> None
        \n<b>Surface Temperature:</b> Average: 462 degrees Celsius
    </string>
    <string name="earth_info">Earth is the third closest planet to the sun and is the only habitable
        planet in our solar system.\n
        \nIf you could separate the Earth out into piles of material, you’d get 32.1 % iron,
        30.1% oxygen, 15.1% silicon, and 13.9% magnesium. Of course, most of this iron is actually
        down at the core of the Earth. If you could actually get down and sample the core, it
        would be 88% iron. 47% of the Earth’s crust consists of oxygen.\n
        \n<b>Did You Know?</b>
        \nLaika the dog was the first Earthling to orbit Earth aboard the Soviet Unions Sputnik 2
        in 1957. She did not survive the trip. A few years later, the next two Soviet space
        dogs—Belka and Strelka—became the first living creatures to return from space alive—paving
        the way for future human explorers.
    </string>
    <string name="earth_facts"><b>Average distance from Sun:</b> 150.65 million km
        \n<b>Size (radius):</b> 6,371 km
        \n<b>Size (Compared to Earth):</b>  1 time the size of Earth (is the earth)
        \n<b>Mass:</b> 5.972 × 10^24 kg (1 M⊕)
        \n<b>Length of Day:</b> 1d
        \n<b>Length of Year:</b> 365 days
        \n<b>Planet Type:</b> Terrestrial
        \n<b>Number of Moons:</b> 1
        \n<b>Surface Temperature:</b> Average: 14 degrees Celsius
    </string>
    <string name="mars_info">Mars is the fourth planet from the sun and takes its name from the
        Roman god of war.\n
        \nMars and Earth have approximately the same landmass. Even though Mars has only 15% of the
        Earth’s volume and just over 10% of the Earth’s mass, around
        two thirds of the Earth’s surface is covered in water. Martian surface gravity is only 37%
        of the Earth’s (meaning you could leap nearly three times higher on Mars).\n
        \n<b>Did You Know?</b>
        \nMars is home to the tallest mountain in the solar system. Olympus Mons, a shield volcano,
        is 21km high and 600km in diameter. Despite having formed over billions of years,
        evidence from volcanic lava flows is so recent many scientists believe it could still be active.
    </string>
    <string name="mars_facts"><b>Average distance from Sun:</b> 217.02 million km
        \n<b>Size (radius):</b> 3,389.5 km
        \n<b>Size (Compared to Earth):</b>  0.532 time the size of Earth
        \n<b>Mass:</b> 6.39 × 10^23 kg (0.107 M⊕)
        \n<b>Length of Day:</b> 1d 0h 37m
        \n<b>Length of Year:</b> 687 days
        \n<b>Planet Type:</b> Terrestrial
        \n<b>Number of Moons:</b> 2
        \n<b>Surface Temperature:</b> Average: -60 degrees Celsius
    </string>
    <string name="jupiter_info">Jupiter is the fifth planet from the sun and the first after the
        asteroid belt\n
        \nJupiter does not experience seasons like other planets such as Earth and Mars.
        This is because the axis is only tilted by 3.13 degrees.
        \nJupiter\'s Great Red Spot is an enormous storm that has been raging for over 300 years.
        This storm is so wide that three Earth’s would fit inside of it.
        \nIf Jupiter had become 80 times more massive, nuclear fusion would have occurred in its
        core. Had that happened, it would have become a star instead of a planet.\n
        \n<b>Did You Know?</b>
        \nThere are no rockets powerful enough to hurl a spacecraft into the outer solar system and
        beyond. In 1962, scientists calculated how to use Jupiter\'s intense gravity to hurl
        spacecraft into the farthest regions of the solar system. We have been traveling farther and
        faster ever since.
    </string>
    <string name="jupiter_facts"><b>Average distance from Sun:</b> 775.9 million km
        \n<b>Size (radius):</b> 69,911 km
        \n<b>Size (Compared to Earth):</b>  10.97 time the size of Earth
        \n<b>Mass:</b> 1.898 × 10^27 kg (317.8 M⊕)
        \n<b>Length of Day:</b> 0d 9h 56m
        \n<b>Length of Year:</b> 12 years
        \n<b>Planet Type:</b> Gas Giant
        \n<b>Number of Moons:</b> 79
        \n<b>Surface Temperature:</b> Average: -145 degrees Celsius
    </string>
    <string name="saturn_info">Saturn is the sixth planet from the Sun and second largest planet of
        the Solar System in terms of diameter and mass. \n
        \nSaturn’s atmosphere is composed of roughly 96% hydrogen and 4% helium, with trace
        amounts of ammonia, acetylene, ethane, phosphine and methane. It has a thickness of
        approximately 60 km. In the highest layer of the atmosphere, wind speeds reach
        1,800 km/h, easily some of the fastest in the entire Solar System.
        \nSaturn has the fastest winds of any other planet in our solar system.
        These winds have been measured at approximately 1,800 km per hour (1,100 miles per hour).
        \nSaturn gives off more energy than it receives from the Sun. This unusual quality is
        believed to be generated from the gravitational compression of the planet combined with the
        friction from large amount of helium found within its atmosphere.\n
        \n<b>Did You Know?</b>
        \nTwice every 29 and a half years the great planet Saturn appears ringless.
        \nThis is an optical illusion:
        \nEarthlings cannot see Saturn\'s rings when the rings are edge-on as viewed from the Earth.
        They are barely visible through powerful telescopes.
    </string>
    <string name="saturn_facts"><b>Average distance from Sun:</b> 1.4963 billion km
        \n<b>Size (radius):</b> 58,232 km
        \n<b>Size (Compared to Earth):</b>  9.14 time the size of Earth
        \n<b>Mass:</b> 5.683 × 10^26 kg (95.16 M⊕)
        \n<b>Length of Day:</b> 0d 10h 42m
        \n<b>Length of Year:</b> 29 years
        \n<b>Planet Type:</b> Gas Giant
        \n<b>Number of Moons:</b> 82
        \n<b>Surface Temperature:</b> Average:  -178 °Celsius
    </string>
    <string name="uranus_info">Uranus is the seventh planet from the Sun. It’s not visible to the
        naked eye, and became the first planet discovered with the use of a telescope. Uranus is
        tipped over on its side with an axial tilt of 98 degrees. It is often described
        as “rolling around the Sun on its side.”\n
        \nUranus turns on its axis once every 17 hours, 14 minutes. The planet rotates in a
        retrograde direction, opposite to the way Earth and most other planets turn.
        \nUranus has two sets of very thin dark coloured rings. The ring particles are small,
        ranging from a dust-sized particles to small boulders.\n
        \n<b>Did You Know?</b>
        \nUranus\' unique sideways rotation makes for weird seasons. The planet\'s north pole
        experiences 21 years of nighttime in winter, 21 years of daytime in summer and 42 years of
        day and night in the spring and fall.
    </string>
    <string name="uranus_facts"><b>Average distance from Sun:</b> 2.9625 billion km
        \n<b>Size (radius):</b> 25,362 km
        \n<b>Size (Compared to Earth):</b>  3.98 time the size of Earth
        \n<b>Mass:</b> 8.681 × 10^25 kg (14.54 M⊕)
        \n<b>Length of Day:</b> 0d 17h 14m
        \n<b>Length of Year:</b> 84 years
        \n<b>Planet Type:</b> Ice Giant
        \n<b>Number of Moons:</b> 27
        \n<b>Surface Temperature:</b> Average:  -224 °Celsius
    </string>
    <string name="neptune_info">Neptune is the eighth planet from the Sun, making it the most
        distant in the solar system. This planet may have formed much closer to the Sun in the
        early solar system history before migrating out to its current position.\n
        \nNeptune has an incredibly thick atmosphere comprised of 74% hydrogen, 25% helium and
        approximately 1% methane. Its atmosphere also contains icy clouds and the fastest winds
        recorded in the solar system. Particles of icy methane and minor gases in the extremities
        of the atmosphere give Neptune its deep blue colour. The striking blue and white features
        of Neptune also help to distinguish it from Uranus.
        \nNeptune has a very thin collection of rings. They are likely made up of ice particles
        mixed with dust grains and possibly coated with a carbon-based substance.
        \nNeptune was not known to the ancients. It is not visible to the naked eye and was first
        observed in 1846. Its position was determined using mathematical predictions.
        It was named after the Roman god of the sea.\n
        \n<b>Did You Know?</b>
        \nNeptune is our solar systems windiest world. Winds whip clouds of frozen methane across
        the planet at speeds of more than 2,000 km/h (1,200 mph)—close to the top speed of a U.S.
        Navy F/A-18 Hornet fighter jet. Earths most powerful winds hit only about 400 km/h (250 mph).
    </string>
    <string name="neptune_facts"><b>Average distance from Sun:</b> 4.4768 billion km
        \n<b>Size (radius):</b> 24,622 km
        \n<b>Size (Compared to Earth):</b>  3.86 time the size of Earth
        \n<b>Mass:</b> 1.024 × 10^26 kg (17.15 M⊕)
        \n<b>Length of Day:</b> 0d 16h 6m
        \n<b>Length of Year:</b> 165 years
        \n<b>Planet Type:</b> Ice Giant
        \n<b>Number of Moons:</b> 14
        \n<b>Surface Temperature:</b> Average:  -214 °Celsius
    </string>

    <string name="sun_info">The Sun—the heart of our solar system—is a yellow dwarf star,
        a hot ball of glowing gases.\n
        \nIts gravity holds the solar system together, keeping everything from the biggest planets
        to the smallest particles of debris in its orbit. Electric currents in the Sun generate a
        magnetic field that is carried out through the solar system by the solar wind—a stream of
        electrically charged gas blowing outward from the Sun in all directions.\n
        \nThe Sun will continue to burn for about 130 million years after it burns through all of
        its hydrogen, instead burning helium. During this time it will expand to such a size that
        it will engulf Mercury, Venus, and Earth. When it reaches this point, it will have
        become a red giant star.\n
        \nAs a star, the Sun is a ball of gas (92.1 percent hydrogen and 7.8 percent helium) held together by its own gravity.\n
        \nAt the equator, the Sun spins once about every 25 days, but at its poles the Sun rotates once on its axis every 35 Earth days.\n
        \n<b>Did You Know?</b>
        \nThe Sun has inspired mythological stories in cultures around the world, including those of
        the ancient Egyptians, the Aztecs of Mexico, Native American tribes of North and
        South America, the Chinese, and many others.
    </string>
    <string name="sun_facts"><b>Age:</b> 4.6 Billion Years
        \n<b>Size (radius):</b> 696,340 km
        \n<b>Size (Compared to Earth):</b>  109.3 time the size of Earth
        \n<b>Mass:</b> 1.989 × 10^30 kg
        \n<b>Star Type:</b> Yellow Dwarf
        \n<b>Surface Temperature:</b> 5778 Kelvin (5504.85 °Celsius)
    </string>
    <string name="moon_info">The brightest and largest object in our night sky, the Moon makes Earth
        a more livable planet by moderating our home planet\'s wobble on its axis, leading to a
        relatively stable climate. It also causes tides, creating a rhythm that has guided humans
        for thousands of years. The Moon was likely formed after a Mars-sized body
        collided with Earth.\n
        \nThe Moon was the first place beyond Earth humans tried to reach as the Space Age began in
        the last 1950s. More than 100 robotic explorers from more than half a dozen nations have
        since sent spacecraft to the Moon. Nine crewed missions have flown to the Moon and back.\n
        \nTwenty-four humans have traveled from the Earth to the Moon. Twelve walked on its surface.
        The last human visited the lunar surface in 1972.\n
        \nThe average composition of the lunar surface by weight is roughly 43 percent oxygen,
        20 percent silicon, 19 percent magnesium, 10 percent iron, 3 percent calcium,
        3 percent aluminum, 0.42 percent chromium, 0.18 percent titanium and 0.12 percent manganese.
    </string>
    <string name="moon_facts"><b>Distance from Earth:</b> 384,400 km
        \n<b>Size (radius):</b> 1,737.1 km
        \n<b>Size (Compared to Earth):</b>  0.27 time the size of Earth
        \n<b>Mass:</b> 7.348 × 10^22 kg
        \n<b>Orbital Period:</b> 27 days
        \n<b>Gravity:</b> 1.62 m/s² (1/6th of Earths Gravity)
        \n<b>Surface Temperature:</b> 5778 Kelvin (5504.85 °Celsius)
    </string>

</resources>
